There's this principle I love called the
zero effect. It's from a movie I think
in the late 80s, early 90s, somewhere
around there called the zero effect. And
there's this one scene where they
explain what the zero effect is. It is
as follows. If you've lost your car keys
and you're looking for your car keys,
here you are in your living room, you're
looking for your car keys.
The chances of you finding your car keys
are very low because there's so many
things in this room that are not your
car keys. So, your chances of finding
that one thing very, very low. If
instead you are trying to find anything,
your chances of success are suddenly at
100%. You will find something as long as
you don't care what it is that you
found. That's my favorite premise for
brainstorming and for early testing.
Don't lock in your head, I'm looking for
this particular thing. I must find X. I
must find X cuz the chances that you're
going to find that thing are almost
non-existent. But, if you can keep your
brain open and say, "I'm just looking
for something. I don't care what it is,
something, anything. And I'll tweak it
later, I'll play with it later, I'll
find some way to consider this thing I
found my car keys." As long as you're
willing to make that leap,
brainstorming becomes a pleasure.